Guide to the Horticultural Society of New York Records 1811-circa 2010 (bulk, 1900-circa 2010) MS 3033
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Flower Show Records, 1908-2000s; 17.67 Linear feet
  - Subseries III.B. Print Matter and Ephemera, 1908-1996; 5.08 Linear feet
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (bound) (2 copies), 1929-1935 (Offsite-box 98, Volume HSNY-59 & 60)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (bound) (2 copies), 1936-1939 (Offsite-box 98, Volume HSNY-61 & 62)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (bound) (2 copies), 1940-1942 (Offsite-box 99, Volume HSNY-63 & 64)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (bound), 1946-1948 (Offsite-box 99, Volume HSNY-65)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (bound) (2 copies), 1949-1951 (Offsite-box 99, Volume HSNY-66 & 67)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (bound) (2 copies), 1952-1954 (Offsite-box 99, Volume HSNY-68 & 69)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (bound) (2 copies), 1956-1958 (Offsite-box 99, Volume HSNY-70 & 71)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (bound), 1959-1966 (Offsite-box 99, Volume HSNY-72)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1928 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 19)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1933-1935 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 20)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1937, 1939 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 21)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1947-1948 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 22)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1951 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 23)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1952-1954 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 24)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1957-1958 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 25)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1959-1966 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 2)
    - International Flower Show: Official Program (loose), 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 3)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound) (2 copies), 1913-1915 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-73 & 74)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound) (2 copies), 1916-1928 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-75 & 76)
      Copy 2 (HSNY-76) is incomplete.
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound), 1929-1932 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-77)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound), 1929-1941 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-78)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound) (2 copies), 1933-1936 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-79 & 80)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound), 1937-1947 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-81)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound), 1946-1954 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-82)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound) (2 copies), 1948-1951 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-83 & 84)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound) (2 copies), 1952-1956 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-85 & 86)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound), 1956-1967 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-87)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound) (2 copies), 1957-1962 (Offsite-box 100, Volume HSNY-88, Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-89)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound), 1963-1967 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-90)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound), 1959-1961 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 4)
    - International Flower Show: Schedule (bound), 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 5)
    - HSNY: Schedule of Classes and Premiums, 1908-1918 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-91)
    - HSNY: Schedule of Classes and Premiums, 1919-1935 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-92)
    - HSNY: Programs, 1922-1950 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-93)
    - HSNY: Programs (2 copies), 1932-1950 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-94 & 95)
    - HSNY: Programs (2 copies), 1951-1958 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-96 & 97)
    - HSNY: Programs / Flower Show Book (bound) (2 copies), 1950-1958 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-98 & 99)
    - HSNY: Programs / Flower Show Book (loose), 1952-1956 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 6)
    - HSNY: Programs (2 copies), 1958-1964 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-100 & 101)
    - HSNY: Programs / Flower Show Book (2 copies), 1958-1965 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-102 & 103)
    - HSNY: Autumn Exhibitions (bound), 1946-1948 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-104)
    - HSNY: Autumn Exhibitions (bound), 1949-1953 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-105)
    - HSNY: Autumn Exhibitions (loose), 1946, 1949-1953 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 7)
    - HSNY: Narcissus & Spring Shows (bound), 1936-1949 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-106)
    - HSNY: Narcissus & Spring Shows (bound), 1950-1958 (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-107)
    - HSNY: Narcissus Shows (loose), 1949-1950, 1952 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 8)
    - HSNY: Miscellaneous flower show programs, 1939-1952 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 9)
      Includes, among others, Brooklyn Botanic Garden leaflet on its exhibit of house plants at the International Flower Show (1939), Victory Garden Harvest Show (1943), Spring Show for the benefit of the Red Cross (1943, 1945), Gladiolus Show (1945), Calendar of Flower Compositions (1950-51).
    - HSNY: Flower Show Schedule, 1956-1959 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 10)
    - HSNY: Flower Show Schedule, 1960-1963 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 11)
    - HSNY: Flower Show Schedule, 1964-1967 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 12)
    - HSNY: Flower Show Schedule, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 13)
    - HSNY: Flower Show Schedule, 1971-1973 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 14)
    - HSNY: New York Flower Show Program, 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 15)
    - HSNY: New York Flower Show Program, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 16)
    - HSNY: New York Flower Show Program, 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 17)
    - HSNY: New York Flower Show Program, 1991 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 18)
    - HSNY: New York Flower Show Program, 1992-1993 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 19)
    - HSNY: New York Flower Show Program, 1995-1996 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 20)
    - HSNY: Rockefeller Center Flower & Garden Show Program, 1994 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 21)
    - HSNY: Flower Show ephemera, 1984-1989 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
    - HSNY: Flower Show ephemera, 1990-1992 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
    - HSNY: Flower Show ephemera, 1993 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 3)
    - HSNY: Flower Show ephemera, 1995-1996 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 4)
    - HSNY: Flower Show ephemera, undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 5)
  - Subseries III.C. Photographs and Scrapbooks, 1916-1998; 5.83 Linear feet
    This subseries includes images (i.e., photographic prints, slides, glass lantern slides, negatives, and contact prints) of the International Flower Show (1916-1969), the New York Flower Show (1936-1996, with scrapbooks for the 1988, 1992, 1993, and 1995 shows; note that there was no 1994 New York Flower Show), the Bryant Park Flower Show (1969-1978, with a scrapbook honoring the achievements of Henrietta Sedgwick Lockwood, creator of the Bryant Park Flower Show), and a handful of smaller shows, like the Rockefeller Center Flower Show (1994), Boston Flower Show (1995), and Philadelphia Flower Show (1981, 1998).
    This subseries is organized by name of flower show, then chronologically.
    - International Flower Show, 1916-1933 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1)
    - International Flower Show, 1934-1939 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 2)
    - International Flower Show, 1940-1949 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3)
    - International Flower Show (lantern slides), 1948 (Box 14, Folder 1-21)
    - International Flower Show (lantern slides), 1949 (Box 14, Folder 22-39)
    - International Flower Show (lantern slides), 1949 (Box 15, Folder 1-13)
    - International Flower Show, 1950-1958 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 4)
    - International Flower Show, 1959 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 5)
    - International Flower Show, ca. 1960-1964, 1969 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 6)
    - International Flower Show (2 folders), undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 7-8)
    - New York Flower Show, 1936-1939, 1949 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 9)
    - New York Flower Show, 1958-1961 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 10)
    - New York Flower Show, 1962-1963 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 11)
    - New York Flower Show, ca. 1960s (Offsite-box 16, Folder 12)
    - New York Flower Show, 1976, 1980-1983 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 13)
    - New York Flower Show, 1984 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 14)
    - New York Flower Show (2 folders), 1985 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 15-16)
    - New York Flower Show & Benefit (3 folders), 1985-1986 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 17-19)
    - New York Flower Show, 1986 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 20)
    - New York Flower Show: "Garden Fantasies" (5 folders), 1986 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1-5)
    - New York Flower Show, 1987 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
    - New York Flower Show, 1988 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
    - New York Flower Show (4 folders), 1989 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8-11)
    - New York Flower Show, ca. 1980s-1990s (Offsite-box 17, Folder 12)
    - New York Flower Show, 1990 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 13)
    - New York Flower Show, 1991 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 14)
    - New York Flower Show, 1992 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 15)
    - New York Flower Show, 1993 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 16)
    - New York Flower Show (5 folders), 1995 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 17-21)
    - New York Flower Show, 1996 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 22)
    - New York Flower Show, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 23)
    - New York Flower Show: Promotional pictures, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 24)
    - New York Flower Show: Scrapbook (clippings), 1987 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 25)
    - New York Flower Show: Scrapbook (2 folders), 1988 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 13-14)
    - New York Flower Show: Scrapbook (2 folders), 1992 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 15-16)
    - New York Flower Show: Scrapbook, 1993 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 17)
    - New York Flower Show: Scrapbook, 1995 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 18)
    - Bryant Park Flower Show, 1969 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
    - Bryant Park Flower Show, 1970 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
    - Bryant Park Flower Show, 1971 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3)
    - Bryant Park Flower Show (2 folders), 1972 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4-5)
    - Bryant Park Flower Show, 1973 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
    - Bryant Park Flower Show, 1974 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7)
    - Bryant Park Flower Show, 1978 & undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
    - Bryant Park Flower Show: Scrapbook, 1969-1973 (Offsite-box 109, Box FF-6)
      Ephemera, photographs, and correspondence honoring the achievements of Henrietta Sedgwick Lockwood, creator and first chairperson of the Bryant Park Flower Show. Includes meeting minutes for the Bryant Park Flower Show Planning Committee (1969: Jan. 29, Feb. 19, May 26, Aug. 26) and the Executive Coordinator's Report (21 Nov. 1969).
    - Rockefeller Center Flower Show, 1994 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
    - Ikebana Flower Shows, 1981, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
    - Boston Flower Show, 1995 March (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11)
    - Philadelphia Flower Show, 1981, 1998 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Flower Shows (lantern slides), 1939-1948 (Box 15, Folder 14-33)
      Includes between one and seven images of various flower shows, such as the chrysanthemum shows of 1939, 1941, 1947, and narcissus show of 1948.
- Series IV. Records from Other Horticultural Societies, 1925-1980; 0.75 Linear feet
  This series contains records of organizations other than HSNY. The majority of the material is from the National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild and its various local branches, and includes records such as annual reports, legal and financial records, publications and correspondence. The records date from 1927 to 1980. It is not clear how these records came to be part of the HSNY's archive.
  The NPFFG was founded in Montclair, New Jersey, in 1893 by Laura S. Stewart. The NPFFG's motto was "share your flowers" and its purpose was to get surplus garden flowers and fruits to people without access to gardens, especially those in hospitals, prisons and other institutions, as well as shut-ins at home. By the 1960s, there were local branches of the Guild across the United States. The records, though spotty, provide a good sense of the activities of the organization, and the letters of appreciation received testify to their impact.
  Almost half of the records in this series are from the Brooklyn Plant Flower and Fruit Guild, which was founded in 1874 as the Brooklyn Flower and Fruit Charity, and joined the NPFFG as a local chapter in 1909. The Brooklyn chapter was dissolved in 1972, and records relating to the dissolution are included here.
  The records are arranged by organization, and thereunder by subject.
  - National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild: History and By-laws, 1928-1970 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 1)
  - National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild: Annual Reports, 1965-1980 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 2)
  - National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild: Legal and Financial Records, 1927-1973 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 3)
  - National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild: Stewart Foundation, 1937-1967 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 4)
  - National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild: Letters of appreciation, 1941-1979 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 5)
  - National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild: Branch reports (2 folders), 1938-1980 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 6-7)
  - National Plant, Flower and Fruit Guild: Publications, 1925-1972 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 8)
  - City Gardens Club of New York City: Records, 1929-1936 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn Plant, Fruit and Flower Guild: Financial Records, 1957-1972 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Plant, Fruit and Flower Guild: Minutes, 1927-1939 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn Plant, Fruit and Flower Guild: Minutes book, 1934-1936 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Plant, Fruit and Flower Guild: General Correspondence (2 folders), 1963-1976 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 13-14)
  - Brooklyn Plant, Fruit and Flower Guild: Programs and related material, 1929-1958 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 15)
  - Brooklyn Plant, Fruit and Flower Guild: Dissolution, 1972 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous clippings and publications, 1938-1969 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 17)
- Series V. Photographs, 1917-2006; 22.73 Linear feet
  Series V. Photographs, 1917-2006 is divided into the following subseries:
  Subseries V.A. Events, 1959-2006
  Subseries V.B. Programs, 1969-1995
  Subseries V.C. Facilities and Staff, 1941-2003
  Subseries V.D. Images used in HSNY publications, 1980-2000
  Subseries V.E. Other Images, 1917, 1940s-2002 (bulk, 1950s-1970s)
  This series is composed of photographs of the activities, places, people and plants associated with the Horticultural Society of New York. The formats include glass plate lantern slides (4-1/2" x 3-1/2"), 35mm slides, transparencies, photographic prints (both black and white and color), and negatives. The series is arranged into subseries by subject, including: Events, Programs, Facilities and Staff, Images Used in HSNY publications, and Other Images. The photographs in subseries A through D provide snapshots of the workings of the HSNY from the 1960s to 2000s. Photographs in subseries E focus on plants, and very few relate to identifiable Horticultural Society activities.
  Events consists of photographs featuring events organized by HSNY. There are images of annual meetings, classes for children and adults, library benefits, staff parties, exhibits, and tours. One set of images documents the HSNY's participation in the annual "New York is Book Country" street fair on 5th Avenue from 1996-2002. (Note that photographs of the many Flower Shows HSNY was a part of are housed separately in Series III, Flower Show records).
  Programs documents HSNY's public outreach gardening and planting programs. The majority of the images are slides of urban community gardens created in neighborhoods lacking access to green space. It includes photos of the garden at Riker's Island prison, as well as images of the Green Team, an internship program designed to help people released from prison transition back into their communities.
  Facilties and Staff includes images of the HSNY's offices, library, archives and collections storage space. It includes many snapshots of staff and volunteers at work. A number of photographs document incidents of water and fire damage to the facilities.
  Images Used in HSNY Publications is comprised of visual materials that were used to illustrate various HNSY publications, including the newsletter. Some images are mounted to boards, with notes indicating crop marks and other editing instructions.
  Other Images primarily includes images that emphasize plants, either as individual specimens or in the context of gardens, landscape architecture, and floral arrangements. It contains many images associated with international and domestic United States locations. Of note are a captioned photograph album of World War I scenes of warfare and the related destruction of trees in France (1917); lantern slides of Mrs. Louis Levy's azalea and rock garden in Dobbs Ferry, NY; a photograph album documenting a trip to Japan (1967); sets of educational slides about planting; and two photograph albums of cacti cultivated by Richard Weiler. There are also sets of photographs arranged by the name of the photographer, including those by Ralph Bailey of House & Garden.
  - Subseries V.A. Events, 1959-2006
    This subseries consists of photographs featuring events organized by HSNY. There are images of annual meetings, classes for children and adults, library benefits, staff parties, exhibits and tours. One set of images documents the HSNY's participation in the annual "New York is Book Country" street fair on 5th Avenue from 1996-2002. The subseries also contains 3 folders of slides of various events that were housed together in a binder, in no particular order. These have been kept together. There is also one folder of oversize material.
    Most images in this series are dated, and some are captioned; however, for the most part, people in the photos are not identified
    - Annual meetings, 1994-1995 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - Annual meetings, 1998, 2006 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - Book Country, 1996 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - Book Country, 1997 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - Book Country, 1998 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Book Country, 1999 (Offsite-box 6)
    - Book Country, 2000 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Book Country, 2002 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
    - Book Country, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
    - Classes, 1979-1995 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    - Classes, 1999-2000 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
    - Classes, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
    - Exhibits, 1970-1988 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
    - Exhibits, 1999-2000 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - Exhibits, 2001-2002 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
    - Exhibits (oversize), undated (Offsite-box 107, Box FF-4, Folder 2)
    - Festivals, 1969, 1985 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
    - Flower composition album, 1967 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
    - Flower arranging competition entries, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1a)
    - Library benefits, 1994-1996 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
    - Library benefits, 1997 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2a)
    - Library benefits, 1998 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
    - Library benefits, 1999 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
    - Library benefits, 2000 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
    - Library benefits, 2004 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
    - Library benefits, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - Parties and receptions, 1994 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - Parties and receptions, 1995 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - Parties and receptions, 1998-2002 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - Parties and receptions, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13-15)
    - Press events, 1994 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
    - Tours, 1959-1995 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 16)
    - Tours, 1994-2002 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Events, 1960s-1996 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 18-20)
      Includes photographs of the orchid named for Patricia Murphy, owner of the Candlelight Restaurant in Westchester, one photo with Murphy.
    - Various Events (slides from binder), 1969-1984 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1-2a)
  - Subseries V.B. Programs, 1969-1995
    This subseries documents HSNY's public outreach gardening and planting programs. The majority of the images are slides of urban community gardens created in neighborhoods lacking access to green space. Also included are photos of the garden at Riker's Island prison, which is part of a job-training program. In addition this subseries features images of the Green Team, an internship program to help people released from prison transition back into their communities. The subseries contains one folder of oversize material.
    - Community gardens: Bronx, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
    - Community gardens: Brooklyn, 1976-1978 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - Community gardens: Gateway, 1977 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6)
    - Community gardens: Manhattan, 1969-1979 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
    - Community gardens: Queens and Staten Island, 1977-1978 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 8)
    - Community gardens: Rikers Island, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 9)
    - Community gardens: Unidentified, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 10)
    - Community gardens: Oversize, 1975-1980 (Offsite-box 107, Box FF-4, Folder 3)
    - Green Team, 1995 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 11)
    - NYPL planting, 1990 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 12)
    - Tree Corps, 1977-1979 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 13)
    - Tree Corps, 1980-1986 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 14A)
    - "Our Work in Bellvue", 1976 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 14B)
  - Subseries V.C. Facilities and Staff, 1941-2003
    This subseries is comprised of images of the HSNY's offices, library, archives and collections storage space. It includes many snapshots of staff and volunteers at work. A number of photographs document incidents of water and fire damage to the facilities. There is one folder of oversize material.
    - Architectural design drawings (oversize), undated (Offsite-box 107, Box FF-4, Folder 1)
    - Library and archives, 1941-2002 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - Staff and volunteers, ca. 1960-1995 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16-17)
    - Water and fire damage, 1995-2003 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - Subseries V.D. Images used in HSNY publications, 1980-2000
    This subseries contains images that were used to illustrate various HNSY publications, including the newsletter. Some images are mounted to boards, with notes indicating crop marks and other editing instructions.
    - Photos mounted on board, 1980-2000 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
    - Slide, negatives and prints, 1980-2000 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
  - Subseries V.E. Other Images, 1917, 1940s-2002 (bulk, 1950s-1970s); 17.82 Linear feet
    The subseries primarily includes images that emphasize plants, either as individual specimens or in an aesthetic context, such as with gardens, landscape architecture, interiors, topiaries, or floral displays. The subseries includes many images associated with international or domestic United States locations; while these images often emphasize plants they also include commercially-produced souvenir images of built structures and general tourist travel snapshots. While many of the images have some basic level of identification, most lack a more detailed context and few seem to relate to identifiable Horticultural Society activities (see subseries V.A. for those). Most of the images seem to date from the 1960s to early 1980s, but there are earlier and later views. The formats in the subseries include glass plate lantern slides (4-1/2" x 3-1/2"), 35mm slides, transparencies, photographic prints (mostly black and white), and negatives.